my
life
free moving pain.
Lord, let my words
heal a heart that hurts.
I want to spend my life
ending broken
people.
I want to spend
my life
mending broken people.
Hello and welcome to another 3ABN today
live. Thank you for joining us as you do
each and every day. Thank you for your
love and your prayers and financial
support of 3ABN as we endeavor to take
this great gospel of the kingdom into
all the world. I have a co-host with me
today, none other than Dr. Ivon Lewis.
Ivon, it's good to have you here. It's
great to be here. And I don't think that
um whether they say flood or high waters
or anything could keep you from being
sitting in this chair today. I know.
Excited. I'm tell us why you're so
excited. because our guest today is just
going to bring
we are going to be so blessed by what
God has given him to give to us. Okay.
You want to introduce him? I do. Pastor
Ivra Meyers. He is um he hosts a a
program on the Dare the Dream Network
and is co-hosting another program. He
hosts Battles of Faith. Yes. but with
his wife Atante, but he's also hosting
co-hosting salvation and symbols and
signs, which is our prophecy program on
Revelation. Amen. And I'm so excited and
oh man, the the insights that God has
given you and and James Rafferty and
Jason and I are the students, so to
speak, and we sit there and we we learn
from them. But the insights that God has
given you and and Pastor James, I mean,
there it's just phenomenal. Amen.
Phenomenal. What what what we're going
to have to do is we're going to have to
borrow some of those programs from Dare
to Dream, put them on the parent because
we're going to be losing all of our
audience. They're going to be looking up
Dare to Dream instead of watching the
Parent Network, you know. So, sometimes
a parent just has to say, "Look, we need
this." So, so we'll share it. How about
that? We'll we'll share it. We're doing
that. you. The Parent Network is showing
Salvation Symbols and Signs. Some days
Dare to Dream is showing it every day at
6:30 p.m. Central. Oh, she got that in.
She got that in. Okay, I opened up that
door. So, that's fine. What we're going
to do before we get into our study, we
want you to call your friends, your
relatives, your enemies, everybody, and
tell them to stay tuned tonight because
we already have had a little foretaste.
We know what's coming. And this is
amazing stuff. This is not stuff you've
heard every day. Some of this you may
never have heard, but we want you to
hear it because we believe it's the Holy
Spirit has anointed you, pastor, and
given you an end times message for an
end times people. And I think all of us,
so no matter what denomination or what
religion you are, you may want to
whatever you are, some folk are watching
that says, "I'm not necessarily a
Christian. I'm not anything." Well, this
is especially for you. And uh so we want
you to join today. But before we do,
we're going to ask you to do two things.
One is we're going to use the uh the
science of television, and we've already
pre pre-recorded you at another time
singing a song, but it so fit today that
I said we normally don't do this. Yeah.
But you with your permission, we're
going to have you sing a song in Christ
alone.
[Music]
In Christ alone
my hope is found.
He is my light, my strength, my song.
This corner stone,
this solid ground
firm through the fiercest drought and
storm. What heights of love, what depths
of peace, when fears are stilled and
striving cease. My comforter,
my all in all.
Here in the love of Christ I stand.
In Christ alone who took on flesh,
fullness of God in helpless
babe. This gift of love and
rightuousness
scorned by the ones he came to save.
On that cross
as Jesus died, the wrath of God was
satisfied
for every sin on him was laid. Here in
the death of Christ I live.
Oh,
over
the ground his body lay.
Light of the world by darkness
slain. Then bursting forth in glorious
day.
Up from the grave, he rose again.
And as he stands in victory
since curse has lost its grip on me, for
I am his and he is mine.
bought with the precious blood of
Christ.
[Music]
No guilt in life, no fear in death.
This is the power of Christ in me.
From life's first cry to find the
breath. Jesus commands my destiny.
No power of hell,
no scheme of man can ever block me from
his hand.
Till he returns to take me home. Here in
the power of Christ I'll stand for
hell. No scheme of man can never block
me from his hand.
[Applause]
[Music]
The star.
[Applause]
[Music]
Amen. That's a two-hander. Amen. That's
a two-hander. Thank you, Ivon. Praise
the Lord. So, it's pretty neat to have
it on where we can literally roll a tape
and be singing and then have you here,
too. this she's real tonight. She's
here. This is live. Ivor will pastor
will will confirm this. This is the real
Ivonne right here. But uh anyway, thank
you so much for your music and what you
do for the cause of God and Dare to
Dream. Thank you. And tonight again, if
you're just joining us, we have Pastor
Ivor Myers. Where where are you
pastoring? Where? Tell us a little bit
about your family. Yes, I am uh
pastoring in Campbell, San Jose, the
Campbell 7th Day Adventist Church. Um
four children, one wife. Okay. Uh my
children are Joshua, Jaden, Genesis,
Jalia. My wife is a Tante. And of
course, we host the uh Battles of Faith
program on 3ABN. And um so we've been in
the ministry for uh what over 18 years
now. 18 years. Ivonne was saying, "You
don't look old enough to have been in
ministry 18 years." Must have started
young. He must have. Yeah. Now, how long
you been coming to 3ABN? So, it has been
Oh, boy. Been a while, haven't we? It's
been a while. It's been a while. I think
the first time was 2005. Yeah, maybe.
So, cuz I went out and your daughter,
how's your youngest daughter? She She is
uh she My youngest daughter is 10. 10 or
so. Yeah. That I know. I went out for
dedication sometime. And you had been
here before then. So, it's been a while.
So, it's been over a decade. They've
been coming to 3ABN. We appreciate what
you do for the cause of God. And what I
like about Pastor Meyers is he brings us
stuff we didn't already know. Yes. So
I'll never forget my aunt Mildred years
ago, she when she was watching Christian
television before there was 3ABN
and preachers would be on and one day I
was out there Sunday morning and the TV
station was on and so she went and
turned it off. Some preacher was
preaching and one of the kids said,
"Mom, why don't you don't you want to
hear this Christian preacher?" and she
said, "No." They said, "Why not?" She
said, "Cuz he never tells me something I
didn't already know."
So, that won't be the case tonight. I I
can almost assure the folks that you're
going to hear something. You're going to
learn something that maybe you didn't
already know. Amen. So, tonight, pastor,
mostly we're going to we're getting you
started here, but we won't let you run
with this thing. Okay? We'll be here,
you know, if you need us, but for all
practical purposes, uh we're going to be
here for quite a while. So we want you
again to call your friends, your
enemies, everybody. Tell them watch this
program tonight. We've already prayed
and asked for an anointing of the Holy
Spirit. So we know that's going to work.
But give us a little bit maybe a a
little preview of where where we want to
go from A to Z and then let's come back
and do it. Okay. Well, um what I want to
share tonight is um really about the the
the destiny of God's movement. Okay. and
uh how can we know where we are in
earth's history? How can we know where
we need to go? And uh how can we how can
we look at the word of God uh to
discover what God's end time mission is?
Wow. um what lessons and we're going to
um the first text we're going to look at
is 1 Corinthians chapter 10 where Paul
talks about the lessons uh that are to
be learned from ancient Israel and um
you know in in the sports world or you
know really we have technology let's use
the sports world when when you know two
teams are playing each other and they've
got a series of games you know after
game one you'll often hear them say
things like we got to go back and watch
the tape watch the tape Are they
watching the tape? Because they want to
see where they can do better. If they
lost or if they won, how can they keep
winning? Absolutely. So God has some
tape and it's it's the Old Testament.
Okay. And he he has given us the Old
Testament especially in these end times
to help us not to make the same mistakes
that ancient Israel made. M so he gives
us this this tape if you will so that we
can study it and see okay where are we
in earth's history according to the tape
what mistakes do we need to avoid and
what lessons can we learn to help us
accomplish what God needs us to
accomplish and so that's what we're
going to be doing uh tonight we're going
to be looking at the tape good well some
of the churches nowadays say the Old
Testament's just you don't need it
anymore and they just use the New
Testament so they're going to be missing
quite a It sounds like if so you want to
make sure all scripture was given for by
inspiration. So and it's to be studied.
So tonight we we're excited for you to
take us through this. Amen. Amen. I want
to say something to that as well. you
know, um, uh, I was not always a
Christian. Mhm. And, uh, I didn't always
believe in the Bible, but when I, uh,
when I became a Christian and when I
started studying the word of God, um, I
I have found that there is such a
wonderful harmony in the word of God
that it has solidified my faith in
Christ. Mhm. Uh I think that as we look
at the word and we see and we're going
to see some of these things tonight,
you're going to see that these things
were not mistakes. These things were I
have a term divine design. Okay, I love
that term because you know some things
you look in the scripture, you're like,
"Nah, that can't be coincidence. That
cannot be coincidence." And when you
begin to see these things pop up over
and over again, you know that there had
to be a divine hand behind the word of
God. All right. And that's what we're
going to see. Praise the Lord. We're
looking forward to that. I think you
have a free offer. We do. This past camp
meeting, Danny, you gave us such a an
inspirational sermon that this is the
free offer and it is um the divine
worship service from 3ABN's fall camp
meeting. You can get this by calling us
at 618-627-4651
or email us at free offer 3abn.tv TV and
you will get a copy of this sermon and
it is really inspiring. I hope my uh
vocal surgeon is not listening right now
or gets this free offer because it's
like 70 some minutes. It's longer than
it should be. I was supposed to do you
know not speak very much. I'm still kind
of on vocal rest. So for everybody but
uh my doctor also off everybody else you
can get one of these for free and that's
right. And uh so anyway, yeah, we're
happy to send this out to you. You can
call us or you can email us. It'll be on
the screen. And uh we appreciate again
your love and your prayers and financial
support. So I think right now we're
ready to hit the word of God, right? Oh
yes. And uh let's take us through this
study. All right. So uh let's begin with
1 Corinthians chap 10 and uh I'm going
to read verses 1-6. Okay. 1 Corinthians
chapter 10 verse 1-6. And the Bible
says, uh, moreover, brethren, I would
not that you should be ignorant, how
that all our fathers were under the
cloud, and all passed through the sea,
and were all baptized unto Moses in the
cloud and in the sea, and did all eat
the same spiritual meat, and did all
drink the same spiritual drink. For they
drank of that spiritual rock that
followed them, and that rock was Christ.
But with many of them, God was not well
pleased, for they were overthrown in the
wilderness. Now these things were our
examples to the intent that we should
not lust after evil things as they also
lusted. And let's jump down to verse 11.
And it says, "Now all these things
happen unto them for in samples and they
are written for our admonition upon whom
the ends of the world are come." M so
the the history of Old Testament Israel
has special significance for those who
are alive particularly at the end of
time. Okay. Okay. Um what Paul is
telling us is that the Old Testament is
a pattern and as we understand that
pattern we begin to see we begin to find
object lessons that help us once again
to learn what we need to know for the
end of time. I believe that these
patterns show us, for example, who God's
people are. It shows us the the
truthfulness of the word of God. It
admonishes us and it warns us as well.
Listen, this is the mistake ancient
Israel made. Don't make this same
mistake. It's not that these are going
to happen. You know, it's not like a
prophecy saying this is what's going to
be. Uh it's simply saying look, these
are the mistakes that they made. And
admonition means that there is you know
a good possibility that by learning from
those mistakes we won't repeat the same
mistakes. So that's the goal uh you know
of these stories helping us to see this
is what God wants us to do. So as we go
to the Old Testament we begin to you
know look for these patterns and they
are so amazing because you know they pop
out in places that you don't expect. So
for example
um when you look at the old testament
there were four offices in the old
testament okay there were the priest the
office of the priest there was the
office of the king there was the office
of the prophet and there was the office
of the judge those are the four prophets
kings judges priests well if you look at
how they are patterned in the old
testament or revealed in the old
testament they come in in in an The
first is the prophet. Okay, the office
of prophets. So Noah was a prophet. Um,
you know, uh, Joseph prophesied. Uh, you
have all these prophets that are the
emphasis in the book of Genesis. When
you get to Exodus, you're introduced to
the priesthood. Okay? M uh after Exodus,
you you you go down to the book of um to
the judges where you're introduced to
the judges. And then the last office you
have are the kings. Okay. So the order
is prophet, priest, judge, king. King.
If you look at that pattern, you you
actually see the very pattern of the
life and ministry of Christ. Wow. Wow.
But when he came came as a prophet,
okay, he died, was buried, resurrected,
ascended as our high priest, okay?
Prophet priest and then uh he would move
into a stage of judgment. Okay, before
the second coming where he returns as
king of kings. Okay, lord of lords,
right? Prophet, priest, judge, kings. So
what that means is as we look at these
different offices, prophets, the
prophets were designed, the prophets in
essence were to show reveal the ministry
of Christ as a prophet. The priests
reveal the ministry of Christ as a
priest. The judges reveal the ministry
of Christ as a judge. And the kings were
to reveal the ministry of Christ as king
of kings and lord of lords. By the way,
the kings did miserably. The kings did
not do so well. Mhm. Uh, you know, you
had, you know, some false prophets.
Uh, you know, a a rare bad priest, uh,
Adab, I mean, Naab and Anahu. Um, you
had, uh, you know, some bad judges, but
you had a lot of bad kings. I mean, it
was just like the kings just kept
messing up, right? Yeah. So I believe
one of the reasons is because um the
king is the highest office that God
holds. And uh you know it was they
weren't even supposed to have kings in
the first place, right? But but
nonetheless, God says if you desire
kings, if those kings submit to my will,
that'll be a good thing. If they don't
submit to my will, that'll be a bad
thing. We're going to come back to that
a little bit later, but that's just
beginning to show patterns. Oh wow,
there's a pattern. We just saw one. it
reflects the life of Christ. Um, as far
as patterns regarding, you know, end
time events, so one of the one of the
perhaps the most end time event uh
oriented book in the Old Testament is
the book of Daniel and as Seventh Day
Adventists, we love the book of Daniel,
right? But there, you know, there
there's something in in the book of
Daniel, particularly in the first six
chapters, that reveal a pattern that a
lot of people are unaware of. So, let's
talk about that. The book of Daniel, uh,
chapter 1. Um, and I'm I'm going to
maybe put you on the spot here, but just
see, do you know what's in Daniel
chapter 1? You know, that's the story of
the the Hebrew boys. Yeah. The Hebrew
boys not eating the meat and all that.
wine. Absolutely. So, you know, they're
they're captured and then uh the king
gives them uh meat and wine and they're
like, "We're not, you know, we're not
doing that, right?" Um so, we know that
story and very often we read the story
on the surface, but what I'm discovering
in the Bible is that there's an end time
application to so many of this, in fact,
to the whole Old Testament. M. So what
happens? Uh Daniel, Shadrach, Meshach,
and Abednego, they avoid the king's
meat. Now, what nation are they in?
Babylon. Babylon. So they avoid the meat
and the wine. Oh. Of Babylon. All right.
Ah, that's interesting. Because at the
end of time, there's going to be a group
of people who do what? Avoid the wine of
Babylon. Okay. Yeah. That's Daniel 1.
Daniel 2.
Daniel 2, those who avoided the wine of
Babylon are given special prophetic
insight.
Come on. Come on. Come on.
And they preach a message, okay, to
Babylon, right? So, wow, man. There's a
parallel. Those who avoid the wine of
Babylon at the end of time and in the
end time are going to be the ones that
are blessed with prophetic insight. Oh
wow. To preach a message to Babylon.
What is that message? Hey, Babylon's
going to fall. Yeah. Come out and hurt
my people. What? How dare you say that
to me? Yeah, but it's the truth. Yeah.
Babylon, your kingdom is going to fall.
Okay. So, that's Daniel chapter 2. What
happens in Daniel chapter 3?
An image is set up. Uhoh.
Wait a minute. My kingdom is not going
to fall. I'm setting up an image. And
whoever doesn't bow down, uhoh, is going
to be persecuted. Oh, well, wait a
minute. I'm seeing a pattern here. Those
who avoid the wine of Babylon uh are
going to preach an end time message that
Babylon has fallen. As a result, Babylon
is going to set up an image and command
that all bow down. Command worship. Wow.
Right. That's just in the first three
chapters. Okay. Yeah. Chapter four. Wow.
That chapter is about Nebuchadnezzar's
dream where that tree reaches up into
the heavens and uh Daniel says it's your
pride, right? Cut off your sins. Well,
guess what happens in Daniel? Basically,
in Daniel chapter 4, Babylon's sins have
reached unto heaven.
Okay? and when her sins have reached
unto heaven. So look, there's going to
be end time people who avoid the wine of
Babylon who as a result of that are
blessed with a end time message. They
preach the message that Babylon will
fall. Babylon says that's not going to
happen. They're going to set up an
image. When they do that, their sins
will have reached unto heaven and as a
result,
Babylon will fall. This is exactly what
happens in Daniel chapter 5. Babylon
falls. The writing is on the wall. Your
kingdom is numbered and it is finished.
Your kingdom is numbered and it is
finished. What happens in Daniel chapter
6 is that Daniel is thrown into the
lion's den. He should be dead but he
escapes death.
Those who avoid, in other words, let's
put it together. Those who avoid the
wine of Babylon at the end of time will
preach an end time message. The end time
message is that Babylon will fall.
Babylon is rejects the message. They're
going to set up an image. Whoever
doesn't bow down um will be persecuted.
But when they do that, their sins will
have reached onto heaven. Babylon will
fall and those who are sentenced to
death will escape death. Wow.
Incredible, right? Beautiful, right? So,
wo, I've been studying the book of
Daniel all this time, and I just jumped
to Daniel chapter 7, 8, 9, and 10 to
look at end time events. But you're
telling me that we have a pattern. We
have a tape. Yeah. from from one from 1
to six. Cuz you know what we usually do
is that we we skip one through six. Oh,
those are the stories. You got to get to
the prophecy. Yeah. But the stories
prepare the way for the prophecies.
Okay. Right. So again, we're just kind
of laying the foundation and saying,
"Okay, so when I look at these stories,
I'm supposed to be looking at patterns
of the church at the end of time." Now,
we're going to find that this is true
even in the New Testament. So, let's go
to the New Testament and we're going to
um we're going to go through the life of
Christ. Okay. Now, now this is really
really to me it's amazing because you
know the Old Testament church was really
like a pattern or a type of Christ. Mhm.
You know, he is is uh the Old Testament
church is Israel.
And if you remember um Israel was called
out of Egypt. Okay. When Jesus was a
baby, he was sent into Egypt. You know,
his father took him into Egypt. And so
it says so that it would be fulfilled
out of Egypt. Okay? Have I called my
son. Remember when Egypt was called out,
God told Moses to tell Pharaoh, "Let my
son go."
He's talking about the nation of Israel.
"Let my son go that he may worship me in
the wilderness." Right? Okay. So, Old
Testament Israel is a type of Jesus
Christ,
but Jesus Christ himself is a type.
Okay, now don't throw the stone. Hold on
a second, pastor. What did you just say?
Jesus can't be a type. He's in the New
Testament. But watch this. Jesus, his he
is the body the body of the the church
makes up the body of Christ. Does that
make sense? Mhm. The church is the body
of Christ. So if the church is the body
of Christ, we think about that. The body
of Christ, right? As little stones,
right? We make up the the whole church.
We make up the building. But the
building is the body of Christ. Meaning
we are to reflect the image of Christ.
So whatever the body of Christ does, the
literal body of Christ does would be a
foreshadow of the body of the church.
Okay? So here's what I mean. Um Jesus of
course was born. Okay. Came as a man,
was born. Well, if we were to make a
parallel to the church, we would have
the the birth of the church. Okay.
Sounds okay. Well, of course, the church
is is born. Jesus was born. Okay. Is
that really a coincidence? Well, wait a
minute. Jesus was baptized. Now, a lot
of people when they hear the word
church, they think of Catholic church,
right? So, are we talking about we're
talking about the New Testament church.
So before even any so-called
denomination, we're talking about the
birth of the New Testament church,
right? Um day of Pentecost. Um the
church was baptized just as Christ was
baptized. So birth of the church, the
church is I mean birth of Christ, he is
baptized. Birth of the church, the
church is baptized. Okay. So that's all
Matthew chapter 1 and Matthew chapter 2.
In Matthew chapter and Matthew chapter
3. Okay. In Matthew chapter 4, after the
baptism of Christ,
he enters into the wilderness.
The wilderness. The wilderness.
The wilderness.
Oh, well, wait a minute now. Did the
church follow suit? Did the church after
its baptism go into the wilderness?
Wilderness. Absolutely. Mhm. Revelation
12, the woman, the church is in the
wilderness for 1260
years, bringing us to the year 1798.
Prophetically speaking, 538 to 1798,
1260 years, the dark ages, right? Mhm.
So Christ goes into the into the
wilderness where he is in conflict with
Satan
just as the church goes into the
wilderness where she is in conflict with
Satan. Okay. All right. When Christ
comes out of the wilderness in Matthew
chapter 4, the first thing he does is he
cleanses the temple.
Okay.
After 1798, right, what do you have? You
have the prophetic teaching or the
teaching of the cleansing of the
sanctuary, right?
When Jesus cleanses the temple in
Matthew 4, um the Bible tells us that
the Jews said to him, "We've been
building this temple 40 and six years.
Will you raise it up again in three
days?" Cuz he said to them, "Destroy
this temple. I'll raise it in three
days." So they actually quote that
number 46 years. We've been building
this temple. Mhm. If you take the time,
don't do that to me. Don't take 1798 and
that 46 years and come up with 1844.
Now you're not going to do that or you
look at it. I know. I know.
I think he is. I think he is. I think he
is too. Yeah. That's deep. Isn't that
deep? Coincidence? No. No. No. No. No.
What what what the Bible is showing us
is that Whoa. As we watch the life of
Christ, he's actually foreshadowing the
history of the church. Wow. Wow. Right.
Mhm. After he after he does this, he
begins his preaching, teaching, and
healing work. M what is the church
doing? Yeah. What's the church to be
doing after 1844? What is she doing?
Preaching, teaching, and healing.
Absolutely. Now, within that time
period, a death sentence is put upon
Christ for one reason specifically,
because of his observance of the
Sabbath. M now I don't know if you
realize that but the first time in in
the book of Matthew the first time that
they're like he needs to die is when he
healed on the Sabbath.
So in other words a death sentence is
issued over the issue of the Sabbath. Oh
he must die. Right. Because not the fact
that he was a church whatever but
healing on the Sabbath. That's right.
They said so it's a Sabbath issue
Sabbath is and you Yeah. Okay. Okay.
Towards the end of his life, he's
transfigured, which would point us to
this was preparing him for the time of
trouble.
Okay. He was about to go through. Yeah.
The end time church will receive the
outpouring of the latter rain in
preparation for the time of trouble that
they're going to go through. Okay.
Christ cleanses the temple one last time
and declares
uh this apostate people as desolate.
Your temple's left unto you desolate.
Just as at the end of time, Babylon will
be declared desolate.
Christ goes through this time of
trouble. He dies, is buried, is
resurrected.
God's people at the end of time, who go
through the time of trouble, many who
have died in the Lord, all who have died
in the Lord, who have been buried in
Christ, will be resurrected, okay, and
ascend to heaven. Okay? Whoa. The
pattern of the life of Christ is really
a pattern of the church. So looking at
that I can we can now say okay
so right now we are we are before right
uh the death burial and resurrection
stage right but we are after the
cleansing of the temple. Uh you see what
I'm saying? We can now and now as we
look at Christ's ministry, we could
probably learn some lessons of how we
ought to be preaching, teaching, and
healing. Okay? Right. Yeah. We're
watching the tape. And we're going,
okay. Okay. So, as as you know, end time
Christians,
this is where we are. A decree is soon
coming up that says, you know, those who
honor the Sabbath are going to be
punished. M so when we get to that time
we know exactly where we are we know
what we know what's coming right we know
that you know our prong of the Holy
Spirit we know that a time of trouble in
other words as we study the parallels as
we study the tape we can see this is
where we are in history now what lessons
can now I'm reading the story looking
for the end time application and you're
you're specifically talking too about
the seventh avenous church absolutely
that's why I said earlier a lot of folk
if you just take out the word church
they always assume, well, the Catholic
Church was first, but this is not what
we're talking about at all right here.
Absolutely. This is actually right 7th
Adventist Church that we can see all of
this. That's right. You know, and and so
when I say that the studying the the the
patterns of the Bible, God is showing
who his end time people are in multiple
ways. Okay? Not just through the
prophecies of Daniel 7 8 9 10 11 12 not
just through Revelation, the book of
Revelation, but he show you can see it
in the book of Matthew who are his end
time people. They're the ones that are
reflecting the movements of Christ when
he was on earth. Mhm. Right. Yeah. Not
to be mistaken for everybody who carries
a certain name will be that. Exactly.
There's a church within a church. You
might say because we're going to come to
that. Okay. See, this is good news right
now. As Adventists, we're like, "Oh,
yeah." But some not so good news is
coming soon because we're going to be
looking at the history of ancient
Israel, and we're going to see, whoa, to
a large degree as Adventists, we are
Satan is seeking to lead us to repeat
verbatim the history of Adventists, the
history of of Israel. All right. So,
let's look at this. Let's go now to the
book of Revelation. Okay?
And uh in the book of revelation, we
have seven churches. Okay, these seven
churches represent the different stages
of the Christian church in the New
Testament. And so I'm just going to do
this from memory. We're not, you know,
just for the sake of time, right? The
seven churches are uh Ephesus followed
by Smyrna, Pergamus, Thotyra, Sardis,
Philadelphia, and then Leodysa. Mhm.
Okay. The seven churches represent seven
periods of time or stages of the stages
of the church from the New Testament
down to the second coming.
So, uh, Ephesus was a church that
started out on fire. You know, and I'm
just summarizing this, you know, we're
just looking at the big picture. Ephesus
started on fire. Smyrna was the
persecuted church. They the ones that
went through persecution, okay? Heavy
persecution, ridicule, mocking, you
know, those kind of things. Mhm. Um,
Pergamus was the church in which
compromise was introduced. This is where
Constantine
um was, you know, basically extended his
hand to the church and the church said,
"Yeah, we we want a king." It's
basically what they said. Okay, we want
a king. They they rejected their high
priest Jesus Christ for a king named
Constantine. We want your protection.
Okay. Thotyra is the church in which you
see um this mystery Babylon power come
on on the scene right dominating the
people of God because of their
rebellion. Okay. Now Sardis represented
those who were escaping the beginning of
the Protestant Reformation. Those who
were coming out of the reformation and
beginning to you know uh uh um uh put
into effect the reformation. Okay. um
reforming what had been altered during
the dark ages. Okay. Um the church of
Philadelphia represents those that
finished the reformation.
Okay. Which brings us down to the
Adventist movement. Okay. All right. And
and then the final church, Leodysia, is
the church that will be there for the
second coming of Christ. Okay. So these
are and you know again it's the remnant
church. Yes. All right. Okay.
So these are the seven stages of the New
Testament church. But just recently, you
know, and I love this is the reason I
love studying the word of God because
the dimensions of the word of God just
keep going deeper and deeper and deeper.
And so just recently, I was studying
this this prophecy and I'm like, wait a
minute,
the history of the New Testament church
is really a reflection of the history of
God's Old Testament people. M it's
mind-blowing. So, let's go through it
again. God's people begin in the book of
Genesis. Mhm. There's a purity with the
beginning of God's people. Adam was
created, you know, pure, true. But guess
what? Adam love just like the church of
Ephesus, that started out pure but lost
their first love, right? So, in Genesis,
you have the beginning of mankind
starting out pure but losing their first
love. sin enters. Well, guess what book
is after? Genesis. It's Exodus. And
guess what happens in Exodus? The people
of God are persecuted.
Wow, man. That reminds me of Smyrna,
the persecuted church, okay, so they
they get eventually get out of
persecution and they enter into the
promised land. Brings us to the book of
1 Samuel. What happens in 1 Samuel?
We want a king. Uhoh. Wait, wait, wait.
But what about your priest?
We don't we want a king. Oh, whoa, wait
a minute. Mhm. So, this is where
compromise begins to come into Israel.
Man, that reminds me of the church of
Pergamus because that's exactly what
happened in Pergamus. Well, guess what
happened as a result of the compromise
in 1 and 2 Samuel?
Israel ends up going into captivity to a
power named Babylon. Wow.
What in the world? Yeah. Are you
serious? Babylon. That that's church
number four, Thyra, which introduced us
to this woman named Jezebel, mystery
Babylon.
Church number five was Sardis, right?
The those escaping and beginning of the
Reformation. Well, guess what? After
Chronicles uh and Kings, you had the
book of Ezra. Ezra began the reformation
coming out of Babylon. and they begin
rebuilding the temple, begin doing the
work God had called them to do. But it
was Nehemiah
who comes along and finishes
the work. Wow. And from that point on,
guess what? Israel is just waiting for
the first coming of the Lord. Okay.
All right. What is their condition when
Jesus arrives?
Oh, boy. They are lukewarm.
Yeah. Leodia, sleep. Yeah. Neither hot
nor cold. Mhm. So when we look at this
history of the Old Testament and we
realize, wo, the book of Revelation, the
seven churches parallels that history,
we come to a to a really
sobering uh conclusion that who if we
are not careful, God's end time church
can be found as lukewarm as Israel was
at the first coming of Christ. Mhm. We
can be caught just as offguard at the
second coming of Christ
by making the same mistakes Israel made
regarding the first coming of Christ.
Right? So now again, we just watch the
tape, right? And God has given us a tape
to say, listen, don't make the same
mistake that Old Testament Israel made.
M now, now here's what here's where it
gets even more interesting because the
seven churches
are a reflection of the seven stages of
the church. It's one church, but seven
different stages of the church. And this
is what began studying this really. I
can't even tell you how short ago I
began studying this. This is not, you
know, this is
this is I was like, "Yeah, I think this
is I need to share this."
The seven stages of of the of the church
in a way parallel the seven seven stages
within God's end time movement.
In other words, hey, when we started,
guess how we started? Started on fire
movement. Yeah. Yeah. We Ephesus. We
were Ephesus, man. Ephesus, you know,
excited preaching pre-1844,
preaching this message, just excited
about the what we were what we were
understanding as a people. And then,
amazingly enough, we go through this
Smyrna stage, persecuted, mocked. Oh
yeah, you guys believed what? That Jesus
was coming when? Haha.
Right. newspaper articles being written
up about how we were crazy and you know
ascension robes and all kinds of mocking
because of what we believed. Okay. But
God's movement, God's church kept going
on, right? But here's where we enter
into Pergamus compromise. Oh,
whoa. So, you're telling me that that
but we're God's end time church. You
know, that's not going to happen to us.
Yeah. This is exactly what Satan wants
to happen to you. It's like God is
saying, "Guys, watch the tape.
Don't allow compromise
to come into the church. Don't allow it.
Don't allow it." Right? Watching the
tape helps us to realize, well, in the
fourth church, apostasy.
Well, guess what? Wow. Do we see
apostasies coming into God's end time
movement? I mean just just think back to
for example this is Adventist history
but think back to Kellogg you know the
you know what what was called the alpha
of apostasy right and think about you
know uh certain characters or certain
people who were one time in the church
but then they apostasize and and you
know start you know speaking against the
church or even w within the church but
teaching things that are uh right
we're in that stage right now we're
there right now so guess What? Guess
what, man? Guess where I want to be?
Church number five, the beginning of the
of a reformation. I think we've seen
that happen. There are people within
God's movement who are like, you know,
hey, where are we going as a church? We
need to we need to have reformation and
revival. And that beginning, you know,
we've seen that beginning, but guess
what? We need to get to Philadelphia
because Philadelphia is what completes
the Reformation,
right? and what prepares us to be
waiting in a right state of mind for the
second coming of Christ. In other words,
God is trying to, you know, we've gone
through our Ephesus stage, we've gone
through our Smyrna, we're going through
a pergamus, we're going through a side
thigh tyra where different, you know, we
got to be careful in the church. This is
not saying the church is an apostasy.
It's saying that there is apostasy
inside the church. Right. That's right.
So, so yeah, we've got to be careful
about what we listen to and what we hear
and those kind of things, but ultimately
God is like, "Look, I this is what
Satan's trying to do. I want you to
finish the Reformation." Mhm.
Philadelphia does that. But guess what
the word Philadelphia means?
Brotherly love. Love. Oh, wait a minute.
You mean in order to finish the
Reformation, we have to have brotherly
love.
Yeah. But you know what? I can't love
that brother right there. I mean, we're
in the same church, but no, I can't love
him. Why? Because he believes this, and
as long as he believes that, I can't
love him. You see what I'm saying? I
can't love that one because, you know,
we differ on this thing here, or we
differ on that thing there. But the key
to us finishing the work is brotherly
love. And I'm going to get we're going
to go f I'm kind of still setting the
foundation for where we're going because
we're going to go back to the Old
Testament and see something. Absolutely
mind-blowing. The deception
um is great within the church because
you think about it because
you of course the deception is you don't
know it, right? But when we see other
churches or other beliefs or things that
are obvious, we say, "Oh, we have the
truth." Yeah. Oh, well, I know better
than that. Oh, how could he believe
this? Well, how could he believe that?
Well, I believe this, this, and the
other, so I'm okay now. I I've got it,
you know, but then all of a sudden you
say something I don't like. Well, you
know what? I've heard, you know, and
then you with me, but we still say,
well, we're inside this, so we're okay
because of 1, two, three, four, five,
and we don't really see the deception.
How of all the churches on earth, who
would the devil want to be the most
confused? Yes. Who does he want to stop
the the the gospel? Stop and go. Yes.
Devil says stop and the Lord says go. So
he's going to work extremely hard within
this church. And one of the things is as
you mentioned is the love getting to
that point that we can love one another
the way that we should. And I shared
this a little while ago uh at the camp
meeting but I shared that I learned that
uh brother in the church had a different
meaning from brother in the world. Good.
That's very good. Yeah. When I in the
world, you know, I had my friends and we
called each other brother. That was it.
It was brother. It was do or die
together. It was, you know, some say
ride or die. It was brother. Right. In
the unfortunately in the church, brother
can mean enemy. Brother is a very loose
term and we use that term Philadelphia
brotherly love unless we understand
unless we come to a place where we can
actually have that brotherly love and
I'm telling you that is one of the
things that is eating at the foundation
of God's movement is this lack of love
one for another. So if I see you in
error, instead of coming to you and
saying, "Hey brother, hey brother, you
know what? You're my brother and I don't
want people saying bad stuff about you.
So man, I'm going to come to you and
say, "Look, you don't want to say this,
man, because that might, you know, mess
you up." No, no, no. I'm going to go to
someone else and be like, you know what
I heard brother so and so say, "Brother,
I'm telling you, man, watch out for
that, brother." Yeah. Really? If that
was my actual brother, if that was my
blood brother, would I go to someone and
say, "You know what I heard my brother
say?" Yeah. Right. My brother said, "So,
you better watch out for him." No. You
know why? Because I really think he's my
brother. And as my brother, I'm going to
do everything I can to protect him even
when he's doing wrong. I'm be like, you
know what? Uh and and I'm going to tell
you, I mean, you know, I've been guilty
of that. You know what I'm saying? as a
minister and the reason I can I can say
that and not you know like I'm not going
to say is because I just watched the
tape and in watching the tape I've just
been like whoa have I been guilty of
this Lord have I been doing this have I
you know it for my ministry sake called
out you know certain people like yeah
watch out for this one or watch out for
those people you know it in in in the
name of defending the truth instead of
doing what a brother would do and say,
"Hey, man, let me let me call this
brother up and say, hey, you know, let's
let's look at this together." So, when
we begin to understand, when we look at
the tape and see, wait a minute, man,
according to this pattern, until we get
brotherly love, we're not even ready yet
for the second coming of Christ, then it
begins to really open up. Yeah, I'm
watching the tape, man, and here's where
we made a mistake. And God is showing us
the tape so that we don't make that
mistake. Mhm. All right. So, now we get
into the
All right, let's do it. Let's do it. So,
now we're going to go back to the Old
Testament. I know we're I think we're
Okay, we're going to go back to the Old
Testament. We're going to see So, we're
going to now look at the entire Old
Testament. We're going to see that the
entire Old Testament is a reflection of
God's end time movement.
So, we're going to break the Old
Testament up into three parts. We're
going to go with Genesis to Ruth as part
one. Okay. Go from 1 Samuel to 2
Chronicles as part two. And I'm going to
go to Ezra to uh the book of Malachi as
part three. So let's see. Book of
Genesis.
Um what is it about from Genesis to
Ruth? It is really about the growth of
God's people. Okay. how they multiplied
um how they became a numerous group.
Well, if I look at that and say, hm,
Genesis, the Genesis of God's movement,
how they grew, how they multiplied, um
they were a movement that was heavily
priestled.
Okay, that's good.
uh they were itinerant preachers
moving around you know and and the the
the the
God's people grew and multiplied and
multiplied multiplied and you always see
you know you get to the book end of book
of Genesis they multiplied exceedingly
you get to the book of Exodus they
multiplied when persecuted they
multiplied even more man you know what
that kind of reminds me of the beginning
of God's advent movement you know they
multiplied they grew they weren't they
weren't fully organized, you know, as a
as a denomination, but man, they they
grew. They multiplied. Itinerant
preachers, you know, moving around. It
was it was they were together, but it
was kind of like a loose, you know, what
what have you. But nonetheless, they
grew. God's people grows. Uh in the book
of Leviticus, they are organized as an
official movement, but they're heavily
priestled. Their leaders are priests.
They're ministers, spiritual, spiritual,
right? Um but then we get to
1 Samuel and in 1 Samuel something
happens in 1 Samuel um they ask for a
king there's an organizational change uh
the organizational change I I like to
say this way and you know those watching
will understand um the general
conference uh is is formed the general
conference of uh Hebrew Israelites you
know they form their conference now it's
not a bad
Because God says, "Listen, you know,
okay, you guys want to move to a
king-based
uh uh uh system. If your kings submit to
me, then it'll be a good thing. But if
your kings don't submit to me, it's
going to be a bad thing." Right? So,
from 1 Samuel all the way to Chronicles,
you have this organization of God's
movement, and now they are kings. Okay?
Um, and you know what, man, that kind of
reminds me of the official organizing of
the Adventist church. And now we are,
you know, we've got these conferences
and general conference and conference
presidents and general conference
presidents, which is not a bad thing.
It's a good thing as long as God's
people and God's leaders stay submitted
to the will of God. Right? So now, as
I'm looking at this, I'm going, "Whoa!
Well, I see something here." Because
guess what Satan wanted to happen in
Israel, especially in this time? He
wanted them to get thrown off track.
Mhm. And you know what happens in Israel
at this time?
Jeroboam and Rahoboam
uh uh Reobam is Solomon's son. He after
Solomon dies, uh, he comes on the scene
and, um, and his father Solomon had
really oppressed much of Israel in the
building of, you know, of his city. And
what ends up happening is that after his
death, the children of Israel come to
Raboam and say, "Hey, you know, your
father was harsh on us. Can you ease
up?" And he's like, "No, I'm not easing
up." He begins to exercise kingly power.
And as a result of this,
10 of the 12 tribes of Israel
split off and go form their own
conference.
Oh, come on. Now you have division in
Israel.
Wow,
man. As I look at this history and I'm
going, wait a minute. Whoa. This is
ideal for God's church. Wow. Right? He
wants there to be a split in God's
church. And as I look now and I see, you
know what, we've got, you know,
conservative versus Israel. I mean, I'm
sorry, versus conservative versus uh
liberal. Um, we have divisions based on
race. We have divisions based on what
you like versus what you you've got all
these divisions within God's church. And
it just hit me like, whoa, are we making
the same mistake that ancient Israel
made? And you know what? God had to
humble Israel. He had to One, one side
was called Judah. Those were the two
tribes. The other side was called
Israel, the 10 tribes. And both were
pointing the finger at the other. You're
the cause of the separation. No, no, no.
You're the cause of the separation. And
as I as I sit back and I look and I'm
going, I'm watching the tape and my mind
is blown. I guess right now my mind is
blown. M because
is God showing us something? He is. Is
God trying to tell us, "My children?
Look at what happened in the past. Don't
make that same mistake."
Is that what he's trying to tell us? Oh,
absolutely. No, no doubt in my mind.
We've only got about a minute and a half
for this first hour, and this is some
good stuff, isn't it? I mean, it really
is deep. Some good stuff. And when you
look at it to where we are and for those
of you within our church, you you know
the things that we're looking at. We've
had fall counsel and all these things
that's you know happening and what
direction that people are going. So
that's why we need to look back to road
map. That's right. We need to look back
what happened before. Watch the tape. I
like that illustration. Go back and
watch the tape and then say, can we
learn from this? That's right. Can we
learn from this? Because if we haven't
learned from it, we've done no good. You
mentioned they will go back and watch
the football tape or the basketball
tape. If you go back and watch great
ball player and you want to say, "Okay,
he's doing this. Let's learn how to play
defense on Kobe." But if you don't, you
just say, "Oh, yeah. Kobe's a good
player. Next time he's going to beat you
again, right?" Yep. Going to do this.
Less we forget. Less we forget.
Absolutely. Well, let's uh give the
offer one more time. Then we're going to
take a short break and we don't want you
to go away because we're going to be
back for another hour after this. But uh
why don't you give the offer again? Yes,
we have the um worship service from camp
meeting our fall camp meeting and all
you have to do is give us and Danny is
speaking and it was really
inspirational. All you have to do is
give us a call at 618-627-4651
or uh email us at free offer at 3abn.tv.
All right, good job. We're going to be
back in just a moment. Don't go away.
[Music]
Welcome back to 3ABN Today live. And
again, thank you for joining us. If
you're just joining us, you missed a
great first hour. So, I'm sure you'll be
able to call and they'll tell you how
you can get a copy of this or if you got
your my SDA box that you can go back and
watch it any time that you want. And I'm
going to encourage a lot of folk to get
this my SDA box, Ivon, because what it
does, you hook it up to your television.
All you need is the internet and you can
go back and get programming on demand.
Yes. and programs like this one time for
somebody like my simple mind is not
going to get all of this. So I've got to
go back several times and you know of
course we can still send you the DVDs
and if you want to but uh you may want
to write us and find out how to get your
my SDA box that has all these Adventist
channels on them and it gets a great
picture. It hooks up to your television
instead of your um you know just
computer. So, people like to see on
their big 70inch screen or whatever
they've got, but we encourage you to do
it. We've been having a great time with
my co-host here tonight, Dr. Ivon Lewis
and Pastor Ivor Meyers. And uh thank you
so much. And we've been studying, we've
been studying from Genesis to Revelation
already, you know, but showing it in a
relevance for today. And that's what's
so important and I think what God is
putting on your heart because so many
people and there's actually whole we can
call them denominations but whole groups
of people that are Christians that say
we don't even need the Old Testament or
we don't need Daniel Revelation. My
pastor says oh I've had people tell me
my pastor says that that has nothing to
do with us. We don't know what scary
monsters got to do with us today. You
know all of these things. So what you're
saying is this has been a road map. It's
been something we can go back a tape you
you set as a game tape watching you know
your competition that's playing or what
have you to study them that from Genesis
to Revelation God has sprinkled that all
through. Yes. But we have to study to
show ourselves approved. So all of us
aren't doing that but I'm glad you're
doing it and we can learn from you. And
so we're looking at a church that
started out as a a movement and as a
people and you're taking us from Genesis
literally, you know, through Revelation,
but going through the seven churches and
finding out that we start out as a
movement and then we end up before the
worst part is is after we go through
persecution and everything, but then we
get to a point where we believe we're
living now. And I think he said that's
called the seventh church, Leadyia. Yes.
So now we've got to decide what do we do
because Leadyia is a sleepy church and
yet right before Jesus comes some great
revival and reformation takes place.
That's right. How does it do it? Through
people just like him. Yes. Presenting
the word of truth and getting it to
where the individuals like like us and
those of you at home can all of a sudden
hit us. Man, yes. This is amazing. And
you know what? Anybody who says there's
no God, what you're doing every time you
take us through even one book of the
Bible and show us Jesus in the middle of
it, all the comparisons, showing us
this, this is design. I mean, this is
amazing that every one of these. Now,
it'd be different if you said, you know,
these books and this book doesn't apply.
But if you look at this book, Yeah. you
can see some similarities.
But here you're going through the entire
Bible and Jesus of course is in the in
there. But it's a it's to look back for
us and to see where we are today. Yes.
And I think what he was saying was we
have to learn from the mistakes of those
before us. Yes. Lest we fall in the same
ditch. That's right. Absolutely right.
Absolutely. Less we fall. So we don't
want to do that. That's it. So, what
we're going to do, normally we would
have another song, but you've got a lot
of information that we want you to
impart to us today. So, I think we'll go
back. You got any questions or comments
before we I It's just fascinating to me
how divine design, how, as you just
said, too, how God just put all of the
stuff together on these in these
different books. Every book reflects
Christ. Every book. Yes. It's to me,
that's just amazing because it can't be
coincidence. That's right. Is it
coincidence or providence, right? Divine
providence. It's divine providence. It's
amazing. So, absolutely. This is great.
Your your study of the word is such a
blessing because like Danny was saying,
we can we can learn from what you're
teaching us. So, this is great. Some
some of the folk will know if you watch
from the beginning, I said I couldn't
have kept her off this program if I
wanted to. She she wanted to be on this
program and she's not one who wants to
be on television or says, "Oh, I want to
be." But on this one, she's like, "I
really would love to be there with
Pastor Ivor." So, u Oh, yeah. It's been
good, isn't it? Thank you. Yes. Good.
Good. For sure. Well, I definitely want
to encourage people to, you know, know
that, you know, you can go to the word
of God yourself and find and find these
same things, you know. So, it's not God
giving a special gift, you know, to an
individual here or an individual there.
God wants his people. Yes. You know, to
to have he to have access to all of
this. So, you know, if we like just say,
"Lord, show me and I'm going to get into
the word of God and and Lord, I need you
to open my eyes." This is this is
something that he these p he wants all
of us to watch the tape, right? So,
there are going to be things on the tape
that I don't see that someone else is
going to see. So, I'm sharing what I've
seen, you know, that that others may not
have seen. But that's the beautiful
thing about coming together. when we
come together to watch the tape. I mean,
just imagine if the whole church was
like, "The tape, let's go watch the tape
and begin to go back and go through each
one of these books." And now we're
watching the tape specifically for
those upon whom the ends of the world
are come. What lessons can we learn from
watching the tape? But you're showing us
how many layers there are like this.
Most of us or a lot of Christians, we
read this. Well, Adventists, you I hate
to use the word, we pride ourselves, but
we figure that we're people of the word.
So, we say this is surface reading, but
we're gone to a little deeper level,
right? Well, now we're just going
several more. I didn't know there was
this many dimensions, you know, here.
So, that's really what you're helping
because of your study. Then you're
getting to some some other dimensions
that most of us are missing. So, we're
we're looking forward to this. And it's
rich. Isn't it rich? You just want to
shout. I might shout. If I shout, just
go ahead. I'll shout with you. Okay.
Good. Good. All right. So, um, we left
off talking about the three different
stages of of the movement of Israel. Um,
the first stage, Genesis to Ruth, u
talks about the growth. There you see
the um the God's people multiplying.
They're growing in number. um they are
organized but it's priestled. Okay. Then
you see this transition into a more
kingly uh uh king-based organization.
And God says, "Okay, uh that's what you
want. If your kings obey me, things will
will go good. If not, things will not go
so good." And the interesting thing that
happens with Israel, which I believe God
is trying to show us, I don't want you
to make the same mistake, is this. You
don't see anything about growth in 1 and
2 Samuel, 1 and 2 Kings, 1 and 2
Chronicles. It's all internal,
you know, stuff, writing, bureaucracy,
policy, you know, this kind of stuff.
Whereas before it was, you know, man,
the promises that we're going to be a a
great seed that you can't count them for
the number of stars, the the the grains
of sand, it was very heavy uh growth
focused.
When when they, you know, when we move
into first and second Samuel and K, you
didn't care what the folk around you
thought. That's right. Whether was Noah
there, I mean, going against all the
odds, you know, and saying, I don't
really I'm not going to worry about the
politics. I don't worry about what I'm,
you know, what's going to happen. So
when people were really of a mind say
this is what's happening, this is the
truth. I'm going to give that truth.
Absolutely. So suddenly now you're
saying we're getting to this. So it's
policy. It's it's infighting. Israel
versus Judah. What side are you on? You
you you Judah. Are you Israel? And we
have this in we have these splits going
on inside the church. And and what
happens is God is trying to show us
because guess what the end result of the
of these splits were? Babylon
overtook Judah and Assyria overtook
Israel.
Now I'm looking at this and I'm like,
well God, you can't be saying that this
is what's going to happen to your
church. You can't be saying that. And I
don't believe he's saying that. I
believe what God is showing us is
listen, this is Satan's goal for you.
Satan's goal is to have you overcome by
Babylon,
mystery Babylon. But I'm showing you the
tape
so that you don't make the same mistakes
Israel made. Please, church.
Don't war against one another.
Don't do things that will lead to
division. M don't do things that are
going to cause separation among the
brethren whether it be through race or
anything else some issue some whatever
now let me say this I don't I don't
believe in uh unity for the sake of
unity right I mean we have to be careful
not to unify just to unify and you know
okay forget about error so that's not
what I'm saying no but what I'm saying
is that when we realize who you know we
may be more willing to put down our
battle swords if we realize, you know
what, the issue here isn't even about
the sword, the issue is about division.
You know, if I'm looking at what can we
do at all at, you know, what can we do
to preserve unity in truth,
right? But if we if we don't look at the
tape, if we don't realize that this is
one of Satan's devices, he's actually
seeking to do this. We can be going
along thinking, "Yeah, we're the
remnant. We're the remnant. We're the
remnant." And not even realize that
we're playing right into the hands of
exactly what ancient Israel did.
Absolutely. And and you know,
controversy controversy is not a bad
thing. There's a great controversy going
on between good and evil. It's just
which side of the controversy are you
on? Exactly. And there are people
willing to compromise because they say,
"Well, we don't want this controversy,
so maybe when this person's going way
over here, you're like, well, let's just
kind of, you know, I don't want to fight
about everything. I don't want to do."
But really, all we're doing is standing
for truth. Yeah. My uncle, he was come
from, we'll call it old time religion,
but if if I can use that term, my uncle
Olan, but he used to say when people in
the church were starting to go a
direction away from the foundational
doctrinal beliefs, but yet still wanted
to be in it, he would say, "Well, if you
don't love it, leave it." I mean, why
bring all of this in the church and try
to confuse everybody and try to get you
some going here, some going there, and
bring all of this unnecessary
controversy? Here's what the Bible says.
here's what we believe as a church and
so if you don't like that why don't you
go start your own church you know but
people don't do that because we want the
church to be like us other than us being
when I say the church I'm talking about
a church that follows the commandments
and keeps the commandments of God and
the faith of Jesus. Yeah. There's a
story in the Old Testament. It's a story
of Solomon and the two women that came
before him. Do you remember that story?
two women and they bring forth this baby
and you know in a in we look at this
these two women are coming before
Solomon for judgment and in in it from
my studies I've seen that these two
women and Solomon this whole story is a
reflection of two times two types of
Christians who both claim to have Jesus
the two women claim that the child was
theirs a male child right was theirs
just as their two type of Christians who
claim that Jesus belongs to them, but
one is not telling the truth.
One's telling the truth, the other
isn't. And they're both standing before
the king saying, "Yeah, the child is
mine." No, no, no. The child is mine.
One of them is acting so good that
Solomon, in all his wisdom, can't even
discern between the two. So, you know
what he does? He says, "Bring me a
sword." "Bring me a sword."
It's the word of God. There you go. Oh,
it's the word of God that reveals who
the true followers are versus the false
followers. Who really has Jesus? Bring
me a sword. And when Solomon says, he
Solomon then says, "Divide the child.
That's how we're going to solve the
problem. Divide the child." The true
mother was like, "No, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no. Don't divide the child. Give
it to her." Yeah. The false mother,
divide the child. Yeah. Yeah. Divide the
child. The
The false Christian is content with
dividing the church. That's because
That's right. That's a That's very very
good. They're content with it. And and
and he wasn't con confused because he
was looking at principle. That's right.
And he was looking at what we call this
love. And he saw the loved he saw who
loved. It's a principle of love versus
the one who is content in saying let's
rip the church, let's cut the church. So
the truth, the word of truth being
divided but not in the baby. So he he
recognized the the the love and said
this woman's love for this son, the true
woman was willing willing to submit
herself, right, and say, "Look, look, I
know what I want, but forget it. I'd
rather the body remain united. Oh, come
on. Yes. Right. Yeah. I'd rather the
body remain united. And she was she was
willing to sacrifice herself. Okay. So,
again, back to this story of, you know,
1 Samuel, 2 uh 1, 2 Samuel, Chronicles,
Kings, this division is going on, this
war is going on, this infighting. And I
believe that God is showing us the tape
because he's like, "Guys, I want you to
look at where you are right now. Mhm. I
want you to look at what's going on. I
want you to watch the tape and I want
you to see where this is headed if you
don't turn around. Where this very well
could be headed if you don't turn
around. But I just praise God that you
know the church may appear as it is
about to fall, but it does not. Amen.
You know what I'm saying? So I know that
the end story is not going to be the
destruction of the church. Okay? Because
the church the church is the people.
people who's willing to stand up
absolutely for the cause of God.
Absolutely. Willing to give their lives
unto death if necessary. Absolutely. And
that's who really makes up the church.
Yeah. Is the people. It's not the
buildings, right? We There's greater
buildings than than our general
conference building, but sure it's not
the buildings. Yeah. Not even
necessarily all the administrators, not
the churches, but it's it's the people.
It's the people, you know. So God has a
movement. He has an end time movement.
He's showing us, listen, Satan, because
by the way, who was the king they
selected? Saul. Saul. They selected
Saul. Saul was anointed
but then turned against God. Right. I
don't know if that rings any bells to
you. He was the anointed one. Yeah. That
started out serving God but then turned
against him. Well, guess what? There's
another anointed one that started out
serving God but turned against him. And
that anointed former anointed one wants
to rule over Israel. He wants to rule
over God's people. And so the question
is who who are we going to follow?
Because following that Saul, right, is
going to ultimately lead to division. So
here's what happens. Okay, so what
happens after Chronicles? What happens
after uh after that second section where
they go into captivity, Judah into
Babylon, Israel, also known as Ephraim
goes into um uh is captured by Assyria.
Well, they spend, you know, Judah spends
70 years in captivity, right? And then
the books of Ezra all the way through,
you know, Nehemiah then focus on God's
people returning
and them building the temple.
[Music]
Their focus had now shifted.
We have a temple to build. We have a
work to finish. Mhm. And what's
interesting is that when they came out
of captivity, the distinction between
Israel and Judah was gone.
There was no more distinction between
Israel and Judah. It was just Israel
again. And when they united, guess what
they did? They finished the temple. They
finished the work. So, as I'm studying
this, I'm going, "Oh, wait a minute."
So, as we watch the tape, if we can
avoid that Babylon part, right, and just
kind of skip over that because that's
where they made the mistake. All right,
we watch the tape. Yeah, that's where
Satan's trying to get us to go right
now. He's trying to get us divide. He's
trying to bring, you know, apostasy.
He's trying to bring infighting. He's
trying to get us to focus more on policy
than prophecy,
right? He's trying to get us to do these
things. Oh, if we can just skip that and
go right to uniting so that we can
finish the work, ah, then we'll be ready
for the second coming of Christ just as
that is what prepared Israel for the
first coming. Absolutely. And that
that's why I tell people the church is
and some people say, well, it's
disrespectful or maybe it's I'm pointing
fingers. I say the church is not made up
of our general conference. We can't say
Elder Wilson on down that well this is
the church. The church is the people.
What I say is no disrespect to them. But
it helps you focus on yourself because
now if I don't like something that
happens at general conference I'm over
here. Can you believe what they doing?
They're doing this and I they're not
even doing this up there. So what it
does it's an excuse for people to shift
the blame off of themsel and criticize
others. So I say it's up to us. We're
the church. So you can't put the blame
if something's not going well on your
general conference leaders or your
conference president or anybody else. We
have to take it to oursel. What are we
doing right with this? Because we're
part of this and it's up to us to keep
the unity within the church without the
compromise. Absolutely. But I think
we've already seen that if we stand up
for truth, there's a persecution that
comes. But it's who is able to stand
during that? who who's going to be left
after the persecution. There's wheat and
tear in God's church. There's truth and
error. You know, these things are going
to be there, but God says, "Listen, I'm
trying to show you this so that you
know, you know what to expect and you
know the mistakes to avoid." And you
know, honestly, I I mean, truthfully,
I'm just like, Lord, I mean, I was
studying this like last week. Yeah.
Yeah. All right. This is not something,
you know, I've been, you know, what this
is like I'm studying and suddenly I'm
like, wait a minute. Well, wait a
minute. Well, well, wait a minute. And
then I'm like, what what what it's it's
mind-blowing. So, here's the thing. So,
now I know, look, the place that we need
to be studying are the books of Ezra,
Nehemiah, all those books, you know,
Haggi, Zechariah, those books dealing
with the rebuilding of the temple. Now I
can be like, "Wait a minute. So there
must be instruction in those books as to
how God's people finish the work." Okay?
You see what I'm saying? I I study if I
want to see how the church grew, I'm
going to look at Genesis through Ruth,
right? Oh, when they were focused on the
promise, you will be as a stars, you
know, as the star. That's if I want to
study man, you know, how can we avoid
the deception? How can we avoid this?
Whoa, look, that's what we're going
through right now. So if we study what
happened in 1 and 2 Samuel Chronicles,
we can see, oh, that's what God, Satan's
trying to do in the church right now.
Ah, okay. Well, how do we avoid that?
How do we finish the work? Oh, I'm going
to go to Zechariah. I'm going to go to
Nehemiah. I'm going to read those books
and the and the the lessons I pull from
those books will be, oh, that'll help me
to see how we finish the work. And you
know what? One of the key books is the
book of Nehemiah, right? the book of
Nehemiah, which again, let me see if I
have it in my notes here. This is just
let me show you this. Um,
Nehemiah,
uh, let me see if I have it in my notes
because this is
hope I put it in here. All right,
so Nehemiah is actually pretty simple in
in the story of Nehemiah. Um Nehemiah uh
realizes that you know Jerusalem has
been laying desolate and he is moved to
go repair the temple. But one of the
things that he strongly focuses on is
the repairing of the breach. Right.
Right. Okay. Uh wait a minute. Isaiah
58. Yeah. The repairers Yes. of the
breach. Yes. Now, when you read Isaiah
58, it's to me it's um
it's it's eyeopening because as a
church,
I don't know how well we understand what
Isaiah 58 is talking about. So, so let's
go there. Isaiah 58 and um we're going
to take a look at verse verse one
onwards. So, Isaiah 58
and verse one. And the Bible says here,
"Cry aloud, spare not, lift up thy voice
like a trumpet, and show my people their
transgression and the house of Jacob
their sins." And it goes on to talk
about how, you know, they seek it. You
know, they seek my face, but they're not
keeping this commandment the way I've
asked them to keep it, right? Then he
says in verse six, um, verse four, u,
behold, you fast for strife and debate.
Wow. What debate? Mhm. You smite the
with the fist of wickedness. You shall
not fast as you do this day to make your
voice to be heard on high. Is it such a
fast as I have chosen, a day for a man
to afflict his soul? Is it to bow down
his head as a bull rush and to spread
sackcloth and ashes? Uh verse verse six.
Is not this the fast I've chosen to
loose the bands of wickedness to undo
the heavy burdens and to let the
oppressed go free? All right.
Verse seven. Is it not to deal thy bread
to the hungry? And that thou bring the
poor that are cast out to thy house, and
that thou cease the naked, that thou
cover him, and hide not thyself from
thine own flesh? Then shall thy light
break forth. Okay. When I read Isaiah
58:6 and 7, you know what I see? God is
saying,
um, what are you doing about the poor?
What are you doing about those that are
being oppressed? Mhm. Mhm. And then I
begin to think, wow, are you telling me
that God is calling his people to
actually be involved in the lives of
people in the community, not just preach
a message, but actually in a very
handson way, minister to the poor,
minister to the needy, minister to the
oppressed.
Um, it also means spiritually.
Absolutely. Spiritually and physically
and spiritually and spiritually. But I'm
going to focus on that because a lot of
times we focus on the spiritually as you
know what forget about their actual
needs. You know, I'm going to clothe
them with the righteousness of Christ,
right? You know, meaning I'm not going
to actually clothe them. I'm not going
to actually And when you look at how our
move, how easy is just to say, I'll pray
for him. Exactly. I'll pray for you.
When the advent movement began, the
advent movement was made up of people
who were going into society and
ministering to prostitutes.
Okay? They actually there was a group of
women who would go in the cities and
say, "Okay, how can we minister to the
prostitutes? They were looking
specifically for prostitutes. Mhm. They
brought them into their homes, changed
their lives, turned their lives around,
and this became the foundation of one of
the one of our, you know, worldwide
ministries in Adventism. Um,
our Adventist founders, many of them
were abolitionists.
In other words, they weren't just
preaching freedom, they were standing up
for the rights of the oppressed.
Now, when you think about it, you know,
I I I look today and I'm like, you know
what? as as a church, we're pretty quiet
socially. You know, we're just like,
"Yeah, you know what? That's of the
world. That's of the world. We're going
to preach the three angels messages."
But what Isaiah 58 is is telling us. And
the reason the church grew so rapidly in
in the beginning was because guess what?
They were out there actually ministering
to the needs of black people. They were
ministering to, you know, people that
were oppressed, slaves, I should say,
slaves. They were ministering to those
who were like actually poor. They were
doing these things in a very handson
way. In other words, the gospel had
flesh on it, right? The word became
flesh. It wasn't just the word. It
didn't just stay up there in heaven and
preached to us. It came down and
ministered to us and and dwelt among us
as one that wanted to minister to our
needs and then bade them follow me. Mhm.
So when are we going to realize that you
know what in the early church when we
were out fighting for the poor fighting
for the oppressed we were not fighting
with each other.
But when we stopped fighting for the
poor when we stopped fighting for the
oppressed when we stop when we stopped
learning how to connect because here's
what they did. They connected the three
angels messages with the social issue of
the day.
So hey, you want to know the answer to
poverty? The real answer to poverty, the
you want to know what can the real
answer is found in the everlasting
gospel. The real answer to oppression.
So hey, I'm with you, man. I feel you on
the oppression. Hey, what can I do to
help you? You know, I I I I recognize
your pain, your suffering. Oh, by the
way, you want to know what the real
answer to after I've ministered to you,
you want to know what the real answer to
to your pain is? Let me show you the
three angels messages. And when you do
that, guess what? You have an open ear.
Absolutely. You see what I'm saying?
Because you've ministered to my need.
You showed me that you cared about me.
So now, yeah, show me what you have.
Yeah. You see what I'm saying? And and
and what just like Israel
in the in Genesis to Ruth when the focus
was winning souls was not winning souls,
but you know, multiplication. Oh, yeah.
they were growing. When we get to
Chronicles,
we're fighting with each other. Why?
Because we're just about, you know, this
is my territory. This is your territory.
You know, who's the king? Who who has
the right to be the ruler to all these
all this infighting because we forgot
about the world. You see what I'm
saying? We forgot that our mission was
not to set up buildings and more
buildings and more buildings, you know?
I mean, okay, yeah, that's part of what
we do, but our true mission was the
building up of the kingdom of God. And
so, I believe again, God's trying to
show us. Well, it's the action because
words mean nothing. So, if a person's
starving, you know, and I I've got an
apple I can give him or I tell him about
Jesus and then I eat the apple, I didn't
really show him any love. That's right.
Right. You know, I may say, "Hey, eat my
apple. I just told him about Jesus and
he didn't even accept it." That's right.
was because the only Jesus he saw right
then was me, right? He said, "That's a
selfish Jesus. I'm starving. He's eating
this apple and he's not sharing with
me." I'm thankful for groups like
Marinath and those that are literally
going around the world, not only feeding
people, but the Farleys who have worked
and actually a few hundred,000 people
have come to Jesus because they've cared
enough to go to the mission field and do
these work. Absolutely. But here in our
own cities, we need to do a whole lot
more. I think about naps. Yeah. Oh, and
just the work that that they do. And you
know what, Matt? If the if the entire
church, the members of the church could
understand, you know what, on Sabbath,
instead of me going down going and
laying down and taking a nap, why don't
I use that day the way God said to use
it? Yeah. Why don't I take why don't I
consider what can I do on Sabbath to be
a blessing to someone in the community?
What can I bring? You know, what about I
you know what? I know there's a family.
They don't even know who I am, but
there's a family whose children need
sneakers. So, you know what I'm going to
do? Wednesday, I'm going to go out and
buy a pair of sneakers. Absolutely. And
on Sabbath, I'm going to go
I'm going to knock on the door. I'm
going to run away. I'm going to leave
the pair of sneakers right there. I'm
going to leave a little card that says,
"Today is a Sabbath day. God was
thinking about you. This is a sign of
his love for you." Do you think that
person would ever forget about the
Sabbath? because they would see the sab
the God of the Sabbath. Sabbath is the
day that Adventists should most be known
to be in the community blessing others.
Right? I'm not talking about breaking
the Sabbath, but I'm saying what can we
do to find ways to be a blessing,
especially on Sabbath, so that the
community begins to look forward to
this, man, I can't wait for Sabbath to
roll around. What are those Adventists
going to do? Who are they going to
bless? And think about all the different
things, the ideas we could come up with
to actually fulfill Isaiah 58. If we
could actually make Isaiah 58 a day of
mercy to where our community knows, do
you know how many people we'd be winning
into the church? It would be absolutely
amazing. See, we lose our focus as a
people of really what it's all about
because in the times that we're we're
right now, we've got people in the
church who some are Democrat, we have
some who are Republican, we have some
who are this, and every group that comes
up, and I won't go into all the names,
but there are groups that say certain
lives matter. Yeah. Okay. Well, with
Jesus, all lives matter. But certain
people want to say, "Well, let's they're
doing good." But when you go look at
that, align yourself with any of these
groups, they're supporting
homosexuality, they're doing all these
things are anti-Bible. So, we as a
church and a people, we can't align
ourselves with any groups, whether it's
political groups, whether it's groups,
if it's ethnic groups or whatever,
unless that all lines up with the Bible.
Right. Other than that, we just have to
love people. And what you said is we
don't have to join somebody else because
they got a good idea. It's otherwise
then why be an Adventist? I'll just join
any church because any church, Catholic
church does a lot of good things. I
might as well be a Catholic. But there's
a message, an end times message for an
end times people. And so because of
that, we have to stay focused on what
God would have us to do. But what you're
saying is we need to do more of the
physical rather than just Absolutely.
There are websites and magazines that
spend their whole time arguing
among themselves about well this person
says this and this one well we should
accept this we shouldn't have. There's
whole magazines preachers read the
magazines everybody reads and all it is
is about division rather than unity.
It's causing everybody wants to
pontificate. Is that a word? Oh that's
good. Is that a word? Okay. That's what
they want to do. rather than to say,
"Look,
I'm here for a purpose, and that purpose
is to give the three angels messages to
the world, but I can't." Yeah. We've
turned our we've turned our weapons on
each other. Yeah. Instead of uniting and
turning it, you know, and not turning on
the world, but like going out into the
world. So, even like we with these
movements, you know, Black Lives Matter,
for example, they're, you know, they're
fighting for something, but I just don't
believe that they have the right
solution. You see what I'm saying?
They're the the you know what they're oh
black any movement you know Republicans,
Democrats, guess what? They're everyone
knows this world is messed up and
everyone is saying this is the solution
and we should be saying hey I feel you.
That's right. I feel your pain. What are
you fighting for? Yeah, I feel that the
world is messed up and you know however
you know let me show you. Right. Let me
acknowledge that I feel your pain but
then let me show you. Yeah. You ever
heard about the three angels messages?
You know, man, listen to this. You know,
like, you know, I just think about, you
know, as God's people, we should we
should be fighting the hate.
That's our mission is to fight the hate.
So, when we're like, we see the hate in
all these different areas. We should be
What does it mean to fight the hate? It
means to fight it with the love of
Jesus. And what if we're going out
together doing feeding and clothing,
helping, you know, ministering with
black and white, Hispanics, Asians, as
as Adventist Christians, we all people
say, "Wait a minute, how those all folk
we we see their love in there." And
there's all of these we should really be
to the point that people don't see a
difference in us, right? We're just
Seventh Day Adventist Christians and we
love people and everybody's not going to
like, you know, in fact, all who live
godly shall suffer persecution. But what
a privilege it is. One time May Chung, a
lady that was on our board for many
years, a wonderful lady, she said to me,
you know, we were going through a lot of
things and she said, "Oh," and I think I
was complaining some early years. I
said, "Man, this there people's
complaining about this. are and and
they're doing this to us and 3ABN and me
personally, they're writing all this
stuff. And she says, you know, I wish I
need to do a lot more so I can get to
Jesus treatment. And I looked at her for
a minute and she said, "Oh, you're so
blessed. If you're getting Jesus
treatment, you know, I it makes me want
it, Lord. I'm going to do more because I
want to be treated like that." Well,
most of us say we don't want to be
treated like that. But what she the
point she was making is you know for all
of us that we have to be a take a risk.
We take a a risk for Jesus. So what
you're saying is so applicable here and
for all of us you know when we look at
this through the Bible he's given us
showing us we have options. Yes. It's
not like this is where you're going to
go. We have options of how do we want to
this movement. How we going to respond
as a church and as a people before Jesus
comes back. Right? Because it's a life
and death issue for you and me. We can
do all this stuff we want and go on
these websites and you know I'm smarter
than you. Look at this. No, I got this
answer. And yet the world around us is
dying. I've had people write books about
me 3ABN. And instead of spending years
writing about Jesus and for people how
to get saved, they want to write books
about other people and criticize. And
the worst part is people in the church
will read it and say, "Oh, that's
terrible. I'm not going to support 3A
being anymore." Rather than to look at.
So what you're doing is you're opening
us. Here's our dimensions. We have this.
We got this. We get this. And the
farther we go here, the more the scales
begin to fall off our eyes. Right.
Right. And we begin to see Jesus and the
work that God has given for us and to
ask God for that love. Lord, give me the
love. I can have all the knowledge in
the world. That's right. Without the
love. That's right. What are you
thinking? Uh this is this is so good
because you know we one of the things in
James, you know, where he talks about
faith without works is dead. So, we can
have all the faith we want to have, but
if we're not helping people, if we're
not doing something for someone, if
we're not making a difference in in with
the oppressed or the poor or whatever,
then we are not really being true to the
Isaiah 58. Yep. So, I think we're not
keeping the Sabbath, right? The keep
true Sabbathke keeping is this, right?
If we're not even keeping the Sabbath,
we're not repairing the breach. Yeah.
Yeah, this is so deep to me because and
and maybe I shouldn't bring so much of
the the the close at home, but I don't
know. There's not one church outside our
church, one organization that I know of
that's intent on shutting 3ABN down.
You know, I mean, persecution. There's
not groups out there, the Baptist saying
we got to shut down. Now, some of them
may not like it. There's the Catholic
Church isn't saying, but there's groups
within the church whose goal is to shut
3ABN down. Now, so and and tell me about
that. I mean, I'm mind boggled by it. I
know. I mind it. I know. And the the
good thing about this what we're doing
right here is showing the tape, people
get to see, wow, am I, you know, we look
at ancient Israel and say, ancient
Israel, ancient Israel. H glad that's
not us, right? really man. Am I
participating? Am I being blinded just
as they were being blinded back then?
Right. And watching the tape is so
crucial. It is so important. Yes. So,
look, I'm going to show you this because
I know our time is running out and I
haven't even gotten to the meat of Give
it to us. We got 18 minutes. 18 minutes.
So, Isaiah 11 verses 12- 14. God says
this, "He shall set up an end sign for
the nations." Isaiah is writing it, but
he says, "He shall set up an end sign
for the nations and shall assemble the
outcasts of Israel and gather together
the dispersed of Judah from the four
corners of the earth." Now, Israel,
remember the talked about the tribes
being separated, right? Israel was the
name of uh the one kingdom. Judah was
the name of the other, but Israel was
often uh spoken of as Ephraim. So, I'm
saying that so you can understand what
you're about to read here. The envy also
of Ephraim shall depart.
And the adversaries of Judah shall be
cut off. Ephraim shall not envy Judah,
and Judah shall not vex Ephraim,
but they shall fly upon the shoulders of
the Philistines toward the west. They
shall spoil them of the east together.
They shall lay their hand upon Edom and
Moab, and the children of Ammon shall
obey them.
God here is saying that there's coming a
time where Ephraim and Judah, the two
separate, those separated will be joined
together. They will be one. And when
they are one, guess what they're going
to do? They're going to sub subdue Edom,
Moab, and Ammon. Now, I just have to
juice this down to let to because we're
running out of time. But Edom, Moab, and
Ammon, Bible says they shall or Edom,
Moab, and Ammon shall obey them. These
were enemies of God's people that would
ultimately obey God's people. In other
words, it's talking about at the end of
time, there'll be a group of people who
once disobeyed God who will now obey
him.
Edom, Moab, and Ammon are described in
Daniel 11
under the king of the north, king of the
south. Edom, Moore, and Ammon will
escape the king of the north. It's a
it's a reference to an end time people
who will come out of Babylon and be one
to the truth. But notice how there they
cannot be one until Ephraim and Judah
stop envying each other
and become one. All right, I'm going to
juice something else really quickly.
It's the book of Ezekiel. In the book of
Ezekiel, we find another parallel of
God's end time movement. So, here's what
we find in Ezekiel chapters 1 through3.
God calls Ezekiel to preach to a
stubborn and rebellious people. Well,
guess what? God causes end time people
to preach to a stubborn and rebellious
people to Babylon. Okay. From chapters 4
to 24, Ezekiel is preaching about the
abominations being done in the temple.
Guess what God's end time movement is
about? It's about preaching about the
abominations of Babylon.
From chapters 20 25 to 32 is all about
the fall of Egypt to a power named
Babylon. Just as at the end of time,
Egypt, the king of the south, according
to Daniel 11, will fall to Babylon, the
king of the north, from 33 to 36,
there's a revival, uh there's a revival
described, an outpouring, if you will,
of the Holy Spirit, just as at the end
of time, God's people are going to
experience a revival, an outpouring of
the Holy Spirit. Now, in Ezekiel 3, I
just set the foundation for Ezekiel 37.
Ezekiel 37 is the valley of dry bones.
Okay. Okay. After the valley of dry
bones is Ezekiel 38, which is Gog and
Mog.
Gog and Magog point us to the
millennium.
After Ezekiel 30 and 39, Ezekiel 40-48
is all about the new kingdom.
So the new kingdom, Gog and Magog, would
point us to the millennium and then the
new Jerusalem. Right. All right. In
Ezekiel 37, you have this resurrection
of dead people. Mhm. Okay. Both
spiritually, God's people will be
revived, but also literally, there will
be a literal resurrection. So, Ezekiel
37, resurrection. Ezekiel 38 and 39, Gog
and Magog, the millennium. 40 onward,
the new Jerusalem.
In Ezekiel 37, towards the end of that
chapter, listen to what it says.
Ezekiel, we're watching the tape, right?
Ezekiel 37, uh, and verse, let's see,
them bones. Them bones, them dry bones.
Yeah. Oh yeah. Oh yeah. Ezekiel 37 verse
uh
here we go.
Verse uh 16.
Thus the word of the Lord came again
unto me, saying, "Moreover, thou son of
man, take thee one stick and write upon
it for Judah and for the children of
Israel, his companions. Then take
another stick and write upon it for
Joseph the stick of Ephraim and all the
house of Israel his companions and join
them one to another into one stick and
they shall become one
in thine handh. And when the children of
thy people shall speak unto thee,
saying, Wilt thou not show us what thou
meanest by these, say unto them, Thus
sayith the Lord God, behold, I will take
the stick of Joseph, which is the hand
of Ephraim, and the tribes of Israel,
his fellows, and put them with him, and
even with the stick of Judah, and make
them one stick, and they shall be one in
my hand. And the sticks where on thy
rightest shall be in thine hand before
thine eyes, and they shall say unto them
thus, the Lord will take the children of
Israel from among the heathen, whether
they be gone, and will gather them on
every side, and bring them into their
own land, and I will make them one
nation in the land upon the mountains of
Israel, and one king shall shall be king
over them all. One stick. One. Yes.
Okay. Right now, we're two sticks. Yeah.
We are two sticks. We've got divisions.
We got divisions based upon race. We got
divisions based upon liberal
conservative. We've got divisions ba we
have,
you know, coming divisions. And I
believe that God is trying to say,
"Listen, I need you guys to watch the
tape because
in order for the work to be finished
two sticks must become one." All right.
Now for the meat. Okay. All right. I
don't know if I can take any more.
Wasn't me. I'm going to try. Wow. All
that was preparation for this
for this. Um, the Adventist church
history is in the book of Exodus from
beginning to end. Right? That's where we
want to close. Okay? So, the children of
Israel had spent 400 years in captivity.
We're going to parallel that to the
God's church during the dark ages spent
400 years in captivity. The end of that
time period, God sends a man to Israel.
That man did not want to do what God
asked him to do. He was like, I can't
even speak.
Guess what? At the end of that 1260 year
period, God called a man upon the scene
by the name of William Miller. Who was
really like me? Preach.
No, no, no, no, no. You got the wrong
person. That's not me. Okay. Moses leads
these people out of captivity, out of
Babylon. Just as William Miller and that
message led his people out of captivity,
out of Babylon. Okay. When God does
that, God gives bread
to Israel,
bread from heaven, mana from heaven.
Just as in Revelation chapter 10, we
find God giving a a open book to his
people, mana, bread. Not only does God
give this church, Moses' church, the
church of of the wilderness, mana, the
bread, he also gives them the Ten
Commandments.
Wow. Here's a movement coming out of
captivity. Uh they're given the word of
God. They're given the ten commandments
in Exodus 20. But not only are they
given the ten commandments, they're
given the sanctuary message. Okay.
Oh, come on now. Yes. God calls these
people out of captivity. Okay. Gives
them the commandments and the sanctuary
message. Exodus 25. Okay. Wow.
Just as God called his remnant church
out of captivity, 1260 years, gives them
the commandments of God and the
sanctuary message. Wow. Now, that's in
Exodus 25. So, just turn with me to
Exodus 25 if you will, and I'm going to
see how quickly I can do this because
this is kind of where it all culminates.
In Exodus 25, verse 8, let them make me
a sanctuary that I may dwell among them,
man. How many of us want God to dwell
among us? All right. Yeah. Oh. So the
work then is to what? Build him a
sanctuary. All right. He's not going to
come dwell with us until we build him a
sanctuary.
Ah.
So you mean our mission as God's people,
end time mission is to do what? Build
him a sanctuary. We have to finish the
sanctuary. Nehemiah, Ezra, we have to
finish the sanctuary. when we finish the
sanctuary, he will dwell among us.
Literally. Literally. All right. So, we
know that. All right. Good. So far,
that's just up to Exodus 25. So, check
this out. God says to Moses, "This is
how you're going to build a sanctuary."
Exodus 25:8,
I'm sorry, verse one. Exodus 25:1. This
is what I want you to do. Because if
you're going to have if you're going to
build a sanctuary, you have to know how
to build it. Sure. Right. You need to
know what you're going to use to build
it. Mhm. So in Exodus 25
it says uh uh speak unto the children of
Israel that they bring me an offering.
Every man that giveth it willingly with
his heart you shall take my offering.
And this is the offering you shall take
of them. gold, silver, brass, blue,
purple, scarlet, fine linen, goat's
hair, ramkins dyed red, badger skins,
wood, oil for the light, spices for
anointing oil, and for sweet incense,
onyx stones, stones to be set in the
ephod, and in the breastplate. If I'm
going to build a sanctuary, I have to
know the building material. Mhm. And so
when you look at this, these were
brought by the people. Do you know that
gold, the first thing he said is
symbolic of faith.
Faith comes by hearing and hearing by
the word of God. Do you know that silver
represents the word of God?
The word of the Lord is as silver tried
in fire. Okay? Every one of these
articles that he talked about has a
symbolic meaning in the scripture. Wow.
Because we don't have time, I'm just
going to read it to you. Mhm. Gold
represents faith or hearing. Silver
represents the word of God. Brass
represents steadfastness. Blue
represents obedience. Purple and scarlet
represents the priesthood. Fine linen
represents the righteousness of Christ.
Goat's hair represents his covering.
That was covered the sanctuary. Ram
skins dyed red represents Christ
sacrifice. Badger skin represents Christ
sacrifice. Shitim wood it means a curse.
So it points us to the curse. oil for
the light, sweet uh spices for anointing
oil, the anointing oil and sweet incense
represented intercession, the onx
stones, stones represented preciousness.
And I have verses for all this, but I'm
just juicing it down. Ephod was worn on
the shoulders, the breastplate on the
heart. Listen to what the message is.
Hear the word of the Lord. The word of
the Lord. Be steadfast and obey. And he
will make you kings and priests,
purifying you through his righteousness.
He will cover you by his sacrifice of
his flesh. He will take our curse upon
himself and through his spirit he will
give you light. He will intercede for us
and anoint us as precious bearing us as
precious upon his shoulders and upon his
heart.
This is the message of the sanctuary.
All right. When we build the sanctuary,
something amazing happens. But first,
God says, "I need you to bring the
building material." So every man
brought, some had gold, some had silver,
some had bronze, some had, in other
words, everyone had a piece to bring and
to play in the building of the temple.
So man, someone's strong in faith, man.
Bring your faith. We need it. So bring
it. Some were strong in the word of God.
Man, bring it. Bring your understanding
of the word. All these things were
necessary in order to complete the
building of the temple.
Every individual upon whom the spirit of
God moved brought something. The Bible
says it was literally every every man
above 20 above the age of 20 brought
according to what the Lord had given
him. Now here's the thing. Where did
they get it from? Where did they get all
this stuff from? Because a sanctuary
itself would have cost in today's money
would have cost $57 million in today's
money. Where did they get it from? They
got it from the Egyptian. Egyptians when
they came out of Egypt sold it all out.
That means they were provided with
enough. They had it symbolically.
The experience
of the beginning of their movement
is what they use to finish the work.
Okay? Go back to the gold that our
fathers had. Go back to the faith they
had. Go back to the word they had. If we
go back to that same zeal that began the
work, it's that same zeal we need to
finish the work. Okay, God says bring
it. Now, let me share one more thought
because I know we're I know we're right
now. Listen, you have to read this.
Uh,
Exodus
30,
Exodus chapter 40. By the way, they
brought so much that Moses had to say,
"Okay, you brought enough. Mhm. They
brought it off. They brought it to a man
named Bezale who was the builder of the
sanctuary. They didn't know how to do
it. Bezel knew how to do it. We may not
know how to use our gold, our faith.
Bring it to Jesus. He will complete the
work. But we have to bring it to him.
And now the final thing the Bible says
in Exodus 40:17.
Exodus 40. I'll read it from my
computer. And this is the last thing I
share. Exodus 40 for this program.
Exodus 40 verse
I'm sorry I'm in Ezekiel. I'm sorry. I'm
in Ezekiel. That's all right. I have
Exodus 40. I I just have to find the
verse. Um here we go. Exodus 40 and
verse uh after it talks about Moses
doing all this setting of setting up of
the sanctuary in verse 33. And he rared
the court round about the tabernacle and
the altar and set up the hanging of the
courtgate. just going through this whole
list of everything that he's done,
right? And the last sentence says, "So
Moses finished the work." This is the
last chapter of Exodus. Moses finishes
the work.
Then a cloud.
Come on. Come on. When Moses finishes
the work, a cloud descends.
Huh.
Do you want the cloud of the Lord to
descend? All right. Before that cloud
descends, we have to finish the work.
Amen. We will not finish it until the
two sticks become one. Before he comes
back before the second coming, you know
that little chorus the Lord gave me. I
now build a sanctuary. Yes. Deep within
my heart and all the my praise I offer
up to him. It's each of us individually
need to build a sanctuary within our
heart that the Lord can dwell in so we
see all of the the outside and the
physical. But I didn't even think about
I was just singing that came to me and I
had to think about is that of the Lord.
I now build a sanctuary deep within my
heart and all my praise I offer up to
him. Yeah. What I'd like to do we want
to go to an address role. Soon as that's
over we come back. I think it'd be a
great time we'll go out maybe in praying
for Elder Ted Wilson, our general
conference president, the leadership,
the general conference and the divisions
as they're making decisions for this
church that we can be one and not split
or divided that we can really defeat the
enemy. So, why don't we go to the
address role? If you want to contact
Pastor Ivor, you may do so at the
following address.
If you would like to know more about
Power of the Lamb Ministries or if you'd
like to invite Ivor to come to your
area, you can write to Power of the Lamb
Ministries, Post Office Box 485, San
Juan, California 95045.
That's Power of the Lamb Ministries,
Post Office Box 485, San Juan,
California 95045.
You can call 831-62343.
That's 831-623-4043.
You can also visit his website at
powerofthelamb.com.
That's powerofthelamb.
[Music]
Well, praise the Lord. I can't believe
our time is just about all gone. Thank
you, Pastor Myers, for giving us so
much. Uh, you may want to get your
copies, call 3ABN of this. You got the
my SDA box. You can go back the
programming on demand, but let's just
watch the tape. Well, so why don't we do
this? We're just going to go out in
praying and Ivonne, we're going to ask
you to pray for the leadership of our
church and us as individuals that we'll
comm submit and commit our life to Jesus
so that we we'll be ready when that
cloud does come back. Okay, let's pray.
Yes. Father God, we just thank you so
very much for what our ears have heard,
how our hearts have embraced this
message. Lord God, we just thank you. We
just lift up our leadership before you,
Lord God. And we ask you to please
continue to give them wisdom, give them
direction, Elder Wilson, all the
presidents and conference heads and
division leaders. Lord God, we just we
just commit them into your hands. Lord,
so much is going on and yet we know that
you are a God that sits high and looks
low and that you know everything that's
going on. Our lives are in your hands.
So Lord God, we just ask you to continue
to direct our leadership and then all of
the people in the church. Lord, we just
pray for those within the church that
they will reach out to those outside and
that they will continue to um have a
burden to finish the work so that we can
go home with you. Thank you Lord for
hearing this prayer in Jesus name. Amen.
Amen.
[Music]